Now let's go down and discuss SageMaker Pipelines.
So from the exam perspective we need to learn SageMaker Pipelines at a very high level.
So SageMaker Pipelines allows you to create, automate and manage
end-to-end machine learning workflows at a scale.
So this includes data prep stage model training and deployment as well.
Now a pipeline is defined using a series of steps and each representing a specific task.
And you can see in the diagram here.
So you have series of steps and each step will execute some task.
And SageMaker Pipelines supports various steps including processing step which is for
data processing and feature engineering training steps to train your model using
different algorithms and hyperparameters.
Then you have the tuning step for hyperparameter tuning model evaluation step to assess the
performance your train models model registration step to register model in the SageMaker model
registry for version control and deployment.
So from the exam perspective you need to remember that SageMaker Pipelines is used to
create, automate and manage end-to-end machine learning workflow at scale.
And the pipeline is defined by a series of steps and each step can accomplish a specific task.
And then at a high level you should know what are the steps.
Now if I go to this link that has been highlighted here.
So you can see these are the steps in the Amazon SageMaker pipeline.
So you have the execute code, training, tuning, auto ML model and so on.
Okay, that's pretty much it from SageMaker Pipelines.
Now let's take a look at SageMaker ground truth, reinforcement learning from human feedback.
Okay, now what does SageMaker ground truth do?
So you can apply human feedback across machine learning life cycle to create or evaluate
high quality models.
So now how can SageMaker ground truth be used?
So it can be used across the life cycle of machine learning.
So it can be used across data processing phase where you will have a human or a person
who can generate the data for you or annotate so that we can create data to train the model.
Then it can also be used during the model evaluation phase where a human can
compare and select the right foundation model for you.
And then in the third phase on model prediction,
it can do the model review customization and evaluation.
So essentially SageMaker ground truth uses a human element or a person
across all the phases of machine learning.
So another question is how do you get these humans or people to work on your project?
So you can do it in three ways.
It can be either through cell service, which means you get your own employees.
Second, you can use Amazon Mechanical Turk.
So Amazon Mechanical Turk is a crowd sourcing solution.
So the third way is you can request AWS to help you with people who can
execute these tasks for you.
So just an example, reinforcement learning from human feedback or RL hf is a machine learning
technique that uses human feedback to optimize machine learning models to
self learn more efficiently.
So if you see RL hf, then just think about SageMaker ground truth.
So let me just show you a quick visual of how SageMaker ground truth works from this
URL.
And now you can see I am on the SageMaker ground truth homepage.
And we are trying to train a text to image model.
And for that, we need to create high quality labeling data to train the model.
So now we can see in this image, we are trying to train text to image model so that they can
create accurate and creative images aligned with your intent.
And for that, we need humans who are going to caption the images
that have been shown in this screen.
So how this will work is so an image will be shown like you can see here a cat and a dog.
And then a human would label you can see her ping and he will label it as an object
and then provide some description. Similarly for the dog and you can see it is in blue.
And then it's going to describe the relation between these two objects.
It also needs to provide details on the image settings or description of the image setting,
background and environment and also provide a caption for the image.
And all the data we create here would be used to train the model.
So that's pretty much it from SageMaker ground truth.
And from the exam perspective, you need to remember that there will be a human
who will perform some task across the machine learning life cycle.